# Carlos Mateo Jurado Díaz

Floridablanca, Colombia · linkedin.com/in/engjurado · +57 3057758370 · eng.jurado@gmail.com

Bioengineer with experience in neuromodulation and medical devices, currently pursuing a Master in Artificial Intelligence. Specialized in Machine Learning and Deep Learning, I have skills in programming (Python), data analysis and cloud technologies, with interest in AI solutions for health and technology.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Medtronic

Bucaramanga, Colombia

February 2023 - Present

External support

- Provided specialized surgical support for neuromodulation procedures, prioritizing patient safety and optimizing therapeutic outcomes.
- Configured neurostimulators to tailor therapy to individual patient needs, enhancing the effectiveness of treatments.
- Assisted in MRI procedures, ensuring high-quality imaging and prioritizing patient comfort throughout the process.
- Educated patients on neuromodulation therapies, promoting understanding and adherence to personalized treatment plans.

# **Autonomous University of Zacatecas**

Remote

Data Science Intern

September 2023 - December 2024

- Performed advanced data preprocessing and feature selection, signicantly enhancing the accuracy and relevance of mental health analysis data in academic settings.
- Designed, tested, and optimized various machine learning models to select the best algorithms for emotional health data analysis.
- Built an interactive dashboard for real-time result visualization, making insights more accessible and user-friendly for psychological experts.
- Collaborated with interdisciplinary teams to ensure AI models met both technical and clinical standards required for the mental health initiative.

#### Universidad de Antioquia

Medellín, Colombia

Research Student

September 2021 - April 2022

- Designed and integrated high-performance analog filters for sEMG signal acquisition systems, enhancing signal clarity and overall system functionality.
- Developed PCB layouts to improve signal integrity and reduce noise in data acquisition systems, contributing to greater data accuracy.

### Universidad de Antioquia

Medellín, Colombia

**Laboratory Monitor** 

November 2021 - March 2022

• Oversaw laboratory setup, guided students in executing procedures, provided feedback on lab reports, and managed inventory to ensure seamless experimental processes and equipment readiness.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Universidad Internacional de La Rioja (UNIR)

Master in Artificial Intelligence

Remote In process

## Universidad Internacional de La Rioja (UNIR)

Advanced University Course in Data Analyst for Artificial Intelligence

Remote
In process

# Universidad de Antioquia

Medellín, Colombia

June 2022

Honors: Honors in the 2019-2 semester and academic exchange at the Universidad

Veracruzana in Mexico in 2019.

# **LANGUAGES**

Bioengineering

Spanish: native.

• English: B2.

## **CERTIFICATES**

- Curso de Programación en Python, Universidad Internacional de La Rioja (UNIR), Noviembre 2024.
- Inteligencia Artificial Para Docentes, UDEL, Octubre 2024.
- Primeros auxilios, SENA, Octubre 2024.
- Prompt Engineering for Everyone, Cognitive Class, Octubre 2024.
- Applied Data Science with Python Level 2, IBM, Septiembre 2024.
- Data Analysis Using Python, Cognitive Class, Septiembre 2024.
- Data Visualization Using Python, Cognitive Class, Septiembre 2024.
- Python for Data Science, Cognitive Class, Septiembre 2024.
- SQL and Relational Databases 101, Cognitive Class, Septiembre 2024.
- Continuing Education Certificate in Leadership, MIU City University Miami, Abril 2024.
- Azure Fundamentals, Microsoft, Marzo 2024.
- GitHub Fundamentals, Microsoft, Marzo 2024.
- Programa Nacional de Tecnovigilancia, Invima Colombia, Agosto 2023.
- New Hire Training: DBS Advance Training, Medtronic, Febrero 2023.
- New Hire Training: DBS Introductory Training, Medtronic, Febrero 2023.
- New Hire Training: Pain Therapies LATAM Interventional, Medtronic, Febrero 2023.
- Recurso Humano para Mantenimiento y Verificación de la calibración para Equipos Biomédicos de Tecnología Controlada de clases IIb y III, Invima Colombia, Julio 2022.
- Tarjeta profesional, COPNIA, Junio 2022.